자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
- 예정보다 좀 일찍이네
- 처음 있는 일이지?
- We're ahead of schedule.
- That's a first, huh?
커피 한 잔 마실까?
You wanna grab some coffee?
안 돼. 집에 가야 해
No, I gotta get home.
웨딩 플래너를 만나기로 했거든
We're meeting the wedding planner.
- 어젯밤에 만난 거 아니었어?
- 아니. 어젯밤은 연회 담당 업체였어
- I thought that was last night.
- No, last night was the caterer.
내 말 듣지 그랬어
그냥 둘이 도망쳤어야지
Should have taken my advice.
Should have just eloped.
- 그러게, 지금은 너무 늦었지만
- 늦긴 뭘 늦어. 도망칠 수 있어
- Yeah, well, it's too late now.
- Now, it's not, man. You can do it.
라스베가스로 날아가서
그냥 둘이 식 올려
Hop on a plane tonight,
go to Vegas.
그럼 다 해결되는 거지
Boom, it's all over.
그랬다간 레이첼네 어머니가
다신 나랑 말도 안 하실걸
Rachel's mom would
never speak to me again.
하긴 그게 고민되긴 하겠다
That's the best argument to do it.
우리 장모님도 5년째
그 일로 날 들볶고 계시거든
I've been trying to get my mother-in-law
to shut up for five years.
이거 뭐야?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, what's this?
쟤네 지금 무슨 짓을 하는 거야?
What the hell are they doing?
- 브레이크 밟아 봐!
- 밟고 있어
- Hit the brakes!
- I'm trying.
비상 브레이크를 걸어 봐!
Try the emergency brake!
여기는 베이커 4호
빈튼-힐사이드 교차로에 있다
This is Baker 4.
We're on Vinton and Hillside.
납치 상황 발생! 반복한다!
지금 우리가 납치당하고 있다
It's a hijacking.
I repeat, we are being hijacked.
전파를 방해하고 있어
They're jamming us.
MONK Season 4 Epi. 15
Mr. Monk Goes to the Dentist
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
송연주(kselub@nate.com)
번역수정
홍관호(kwanho_hong@nate.com)
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2006/03/10
방금 트럭을 찾았어요
여기 3일 동안 있었습니다
We just found the truck.
This been sitting here for three days.
고맙네. 현금은 대부분 놓고 갔다던데
Thanks. And they left most
of the cash.
맞습니다
Yes, sir.
이 사람들이 운전사들인가 보군
And these are the drivers.
네. 검시관 말로는 싸움이 있었답니다
Yeah, the ME said they
put up a fight. I mean...
한바탕 한 것처럼
사방이 피투성입니다
blood everywhere
like there was a struggle.
그나마 다행이네
Well, good for them.
범인이 상처를 입었을 수도 있잖나
병원에 확인해 보자고
Maybe they injured one of the bastards.
Let's check the hospitals.
- 총상이나 자상 환자가 있나 확인해
- 네, 경감님
I want a list of all gunshot wounds,
knife wounds. / Yes, sir.
- 자네 괜찮나?
- 치통 때문에요
- You okay?
- Oh, toothache.
잠깐, 저번이랑 똑같은 데야?
어떻게 좀 하라고 했잖아
Wait, is that the same tooth?
I told you to take care of that.
네, 그러고 있습니다
지금 안 아픈 쪽으로 씹고 있어요
Yeah, I am.
I'm chewing on the other side.
견딜 만합니다
아픈 줄도 모르겠어요
It's fine, I hardly notice it.
울고 있잖나
You're crying.
랜디, 이래선 나한테도 도움이 안 돼
얼른 치과에 가
Randy, you're no good to me like this.
Go to a dentist.
- 토요일에 예약해 놨어요
- 아, 무슨 말인지 알겠어
- I have an appointment Saturday.
- Oh, I get it.
병가를 안 쓰고 싶단 거군
You don't wanna use up
your sick days.
안 아플 때 병가를 내려고
아끼는 중이야. 그렇지?
You're saving your sick days for when
you're not feeling sick, is that it?
난 몽크와 얘기하러 가겠네. 자네랑
있다 보면 차라리 몽크가 보고 싶어져
I'm gonna go talk to Monk.
You make me wanna talk to Monk.
세상에, 이 사람들 중 한 명이
곧 결혼할 예정이었대요
God, I just heard one of those guys
was about to get married.
랜디?
Randy?
알아요, 알아. 가슴 아프네요
너무 젊은 사람들이잖아요
I know, I know, it's heartbreaking.
They were so young.
우는 건 괜찮은 거예요
가슴이 따뜻하다는 거니까요
Sweetie, it's okay to cry.
It means you have a heart.
나 좀 봐요
Here, look at me.
랜디는 인정 많은 사람이에요
그건 부끄러워할 일이 아니에요
You're a compassionate person.
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
- 너무 아파요
- 알아요. 아프다는 거 알아요
- It hurts.
- I know. I know it hurts.
남들한테 보이기 싫은 거죠?
You don't want anybody to see you?
이해해요
I understand.
이렇게 할까요? 누가 물어보면
그냥 이렇게 말하는... / 치통이...
You know what? If anyone says anything,
we'll just say that you, uh... / My tooth, oh...
네, 좋아요. 치통이 있어서
그렇다고 하죠 / 미치겠네!
Yeah, perfect, that you
have a toothache. / Oh, god.
- 진짜 아파요
- 그건 좀 오버하는 것 같은데요
- God, this hurts.
- Okay, I think that's overdoing it.
오, 하느님
제발 날 그냥 쏴 줘요
Oh, please, Jesus,
somebody just shoot me.
랜디, 이러면 아무도 안 믿어요
Randy, no one's gonna believe that.
바닥에 기름이 떨어져 있어요
There's some oil on the floor.
그게 단서인가?
중요한 거야?
Is that a clue?
Is that important?
아뇨. 그냥 바닥에 기름이 있다고요
Nah, there's oil on the floor.
환경 보호국에 연락할게
I'll call the EPA.
그래, 이 사건에 대해
So, do you, uh...
어떤 생각이 드나?
any ideas about the robbery?
- 뒤쪽 범퍼가 꽤 손상된 걸 보셨어요?
- 봤지
Did you notice the back bumper,
how damaged it was? / Yeah.
그리고 백미러가 옆으로 접혀 있어요
And these side mirrors are pushed in.
누가 여기까지 이 트럭을
몰고 온 것 같진 않아요
I don't think this
armored car was driven here.
- 몰고 오지 않았다고?
- 네
- It wasn't?
- No.
아마도 더 큰 트럭의
짐칸에 실려 온 것 같아요
I think it was carried somehow
in the back of a bigger truck.
이것보다 더 큰 차량의
타이어 자국이 있거든요
You see the tire tracks
from a larger vehicle.
그렇군
You're right.
아마 폭이 4미터는 넘는
대형 트레일러 같은데
It was probably an 18-wheeler
about 14 feet wide.
그럼 이 현금 수송차를 싣고 와서
여기에 내려놓았다면
So they brought the armored car here,
they unload it.
어떻게 운전사들을
운전석에서 끌어내렸지?
How did they get the drivers
out of the cab?
이걸로요
With this.
고무관으로요
A piece of rubber tubing.
여기다 구멍을 뚫었어요
They drilled the hole here.
여기 플렉시 유리에요
In the plexiglas.
가스를 넣어서 나오게 했군
They gassed them out.
랜디?
Randy?
네, 경감님
Yes, sir?
이거 담아
Bag this up.
- 치통 때문에 그렇대요
- 알아요. 일주일 내내 우는소릴 했거든요
He has a toothache. / Yeah, I know.
He's been bitching about it all week.
- 이거 진짜 치통이에요?
- 네
- What, it's a real toothache?
- Yeah.
어떻게 그런 거짓말을 할 수가 있어요?
왜 그냥 치통 때문이라고 말하지 않았죠?
I can't believe you lied to me like that.
Why didn't you just say I have a toothache?
말했잖아요, 한 열 번쯤
I did, like ten times.
랜디, 오늘 당장 그 충치 해결 안 하면
Randy, if you don't take care
of this tooth immediately today,
내가 직접 뽑아 버릴 거야
알아들었어?
I'm gonna rip it out myself, understand?
알겠습니다
Fine.
왜요?
What?
디셔 씨?
Mr. Disher?
- 맞아요
- 그렇군요, 전 테리예요
- Yeah.
- Oh, good. I'm Terri.
서류 다 작성하셨어요?
Did you do all your paperwork?
양쪽 다 하셨네요
착하기도 하셔라 / 네
Both sides.
Good boy. / Yeah.
접수원은 어디 갔어요?
Where's your receptionist?
야간 접수원이 그만뒀거든요
Oh, our nighttime receptionist quit.
- 너무 재밌어서 못 견뎠나 보죠?
- 그랬나 봐요
- Couldn't stand the excitement, huh?
- I guess not.
B번 방에서 진찰 받으실 거예요
So you're gonna be in room B.
A번하고 C번 사이 방이요
That's between A and C.
근데 길 잃으면 어쩌죠?
Well, what if I get lost?
지도라도 그려 드릴까요?
You want me to draw you a map?
- 찾을 수 있을 것 같아요
- 네, 저도 곧 들어갈게요
- Yeah, I think I can find it.
- Okay. I'll be right in.
디셔 씨, 전 올리버 블룸입니다
Well, Mr. Disher, I'm Oliver Bloom.
안 일어나셔도 돼요
농담입니다
Don't get up. Just kidding.
- 경위님 맞으시죠?
- 네
- You're a lieutenant, am I right?
- Yeah.
보통 한 계급 내로 맞춘답니다
I can usually guess within one rank.
경찰 분들이 많이 오시는 편이죠
여기가 의료 보험 지정 병원이거든요
I see a lot of cops in here.
We're on the medical plan, you know.
예약도 없이 왔는데도
치료해 주셔서 감사합니다
Thanks for seeing me
on such short notice.
괜찮습니다
Oh, that's not a problem.
응급 상황에 대비해서 화요일과
목요일은 늦게까지 열거든요
We're open late on Tuesdays and Thursdays
in case of emergencies.
그리고 테리도 밖에
못 나가게 잡아 두려고요
Also to keep Terri here off the streets.
- 절 걱정해 주세요
- 정말입니다
- He worries about me.
- I do.
제가 정말 걱정되는 게 뭔지 아세요?
바로 요놈이 걱정이군요
You know what I'm really worried about?
I worry about this bad boy right here.
3번 어금니가 말썽입니다
Your number three molar.
테리, 여기 불 좀 비춰 줄래요?
Terri, can I have a light, please?
입을 크게 벌리시고
긴장 푸세요
I want you to open wide,
just try to relax.
좀 더 크게요
좋습니다. 편하게 계세요
A little wider.
Okay, just relax.
알겠어요
좀 민감하군요
Okay, okay.
A little sensitive.
그 어금니에 애착이
없으셨으면 좋겠네요, 경위님
Well, I hope you're not in love
with that tooth, lieutenant,
안타깝지만 뽑아야 할 것 같거든요
because I'm afraid it's gonna have to go.
다음 주에 뽑을 수도 있고
오늘 뽑을 수도 있는데
Now, we can either pull it next week,
or we can do it today.
경위님이 선택하세요
The choice is yours.
지금 하죠
Let's do it now.
그럼 약 30분 동안
마취시키도록 하겠습니다
Okay, Randy, we're gonna
put you under for about 30 minutes.
아무것도 못 느끼실 거예요
You're not gonna feel a thing.
사실은 이 뽑고 나서도
매주 오셔야 해요
As a matter of fact, you're gonna
be back here every week for this.
말 잘 들으시면
끝나고 스티커 드릴게요
And if you're a really good boy,
I'm gonna give you a sticker afterwards.
못되게 굴면요?
What if I'm a bad boy?
이제 숨 쉬세요
Just breathe.
평소처럼 편하게 숨 쉬세요
Breathe normally, relax.
테리가 옆에 서 있으면
그러기 힘들다는 거 압니다
I know it's hard with Terri
standing over you.
제 말 들리세요?
Can you hear me?
긴장 푸시고, 깊게 열 번만
들이쉬세요. 아셨죠?
Just relax, I want you
to take ten deep breaths, okay?
하나
One,
둘
two,
셋
three,
넷
four,
다섯...
five...
테리, 소식자(消息子) 좀
다시 줄래요?
Terri, I'm gonna need that angled
director probe again please.
소식자 여기 있습니다
Angled director probe.
잠깐만요
다시 깨어나는 것 같아요
Doctor, wait, I think
he's coming awake again.
자...
Come on.
이봐!
Hey!
- 무슨 일로 또 오셨죠?
- 배리 본즈 어떻게 했어?
- What are you doing here?
- What did you do with Barry Bonds?
여기에 숨겨 둔 거 알아
I know he's here somewhere.
무슨 짓을 한 거야?
여기 있는 거 안다니까!
What did you do?
I know he's here.
- 여기 있잖아
- 무슨 말씀을 하시는 겁니까?
- I know he's here.
- What are you talking about?
- 배리 본즈 말이야
- 우린 배리 본즈 몰라요
- Barry Bonds.
- We don't know any Barry Bonds.
천3백만 달러나 나간다고!
대체 무슨 짓을 했지?
He is worth $13 million.
What did you do with him?
- 지금 환자를 치료 중이에요
- 네, 치료 중이라니까요
- We're with a patient here.
- Yeah, we have a patient here.
- 우리는 정말...
- 배리 본즈...
- We're really...
- Listen, Barry Bonds.
이봐요
Hey, hey.
그만 해요
Hey, cut it out.
전 경찰이에요
I'm a police officer.
전 경찰이란 말입니다
잠자는 숲 속의 왕자님
Hey, sleeping beauty.
일어나셨어요?
Welcome back.
테리, 괜찮아요?
Are you all right?
괜찮으냐고요?
안 그럴 이유라도 있나요?
Am I all right?
Why wouldn't I be?
여기에 어떤 남자가 있었잖아요
There was a man in here.
테리 근처엔 항상 남자가 있죠
She has a man in here all the time.
선생님이...
You...
선생님은 싸우고 계셨잖아요
you were fighting.
하긴 누구랑 싸우긴 했죠
Well, there was a fight, all right.
이 어금니하고 말입니다
잘 안 빠지려고 하더군요
Between me and this molar here.
It didn't wanna come out.
며칠 동안은 좀 아프실 거예요
There's gonna be some
sensitivity for a few days.
처방전 써 드렸으니까
통증은 괜찮아질 겁니다
I wrote you a prescription.
This should help with the pain.
네 시간에 한 알 이상
드시지 마세요
Now, don't take more
than one every four hours.
깜빡할 뻔했네요
Oh, and I almost forgot.
스티커 드려야죠
Your sticker.
경감님, 트레일러가 도난됐다는
신고가 전혀 없습니다
Captain, there are no reports
of any stolen trucks.
계속 찾아봐
수색 범위 넓히고
Well, keep looking.
Widen the net.
시애틀부터 시작해서
남쪽으로 내려가 봐
Start at Seattle and
work your way south.
경감님, 수송 차량에 실렸던
물품들의 최종 목록입니다
Captain, here's a copy
of the updated manifest.
- 돈은 새 지폐였겠지?
- 네. 쉽게 추적이 가능한 돈이었죠
The cash was new, right? / Yes, sir,
it would have been easily traced.
없어진 건 천만 달러가 넘는
양도성 예금 증서뿐이었어요
All they took were the negotiable
bank certificates over $10 million.
좋아. 추적해 보자고
All right, let's follow the money.
이렇게 큰 금액을 처리할 수 있는 데가
국내에 몇 군데나 있나?
How many fences in the country
could handle a haul like this?
- 알아보겠습니다
- 경감님?
- I'll find out.
- Captain?
랜디, 잘 왔어
Randy, welcome back.
자넨 패터슨과 함께
예금 증서를 조사하게
You're working with Patterson
on the bank certificates.
재무부의 프랭크 데이비스하고
전화 연결해 주고
Get me Frank Davis
at the treasury department on the line.
그 정도 금액을 처리할 만한
장물 취급소 목록을 전부 뽑...
And put a list together of all the fences.
Any fence in the country who's got the balls...
- 시간 좀 있으세요?
- 응, 무슨 일이야?
- Captain, do you have a minute?
- Yeah, what's up?
- 제 치과 의사 얘긴데요, 블룸 박사요
- 근데?
- It's about my dentist, Dr. Bloom?
- Yeah?
제 생각엔...
I think, um...
- 그 사람이...
- 어딜 더듬기라도 했나?
- I think he might...
- Did he touch you inappropriately?
네? 아뇨, 절대 아닙니다
What? No, Jesus, no. No.
제 생각엔 그 사람이
누굴 죽인 것 같습니다
I think he killed a guy.
- 뭘 했다고?
- 정말입니다
- He what?
- It happened.
블룸 박사하고 조수 테리 있잖아요?
I think that he, Dr. Bloom
and his assistant Terri?
그 둘이 누굴 죽인 것 같습니다
I mean, I think they murdered someone.
- 자네가 봤나?
- 네, 그런 셈이죠
- You saw it?
- Yeah, sort of.
마취 상태였거든요
I was sedated.
마취 상태였다고?
You were sedated?
랜디, 난 마취됐을 때 내 콧수염이
다람쥐로 보인 적도 있었어
Randy, one time, I was under anesthesia.
I thought my moustache was a chipmunk.
저는 '그린 랜턴'이 된 적도 있어요
(만화 주인공. 슈퍼 영웅)
I was the Green Lantern once.
정말 굉장했죠
깨어나기가 싫었다니까요
It was great.
I didn't wanna wake up.
마취를 30분만 하기로 했었는데
Look, I was supposed
to be out for 30 minutes.
거의 두 시간 동안이나 했다고요
But I was under for almost two hours.
- 시체가 있었나?
- 아뇨
- Was there a body?
- No.
- 몸싸움한 흔적이라도 있었어?
- 아뇨
- Any signs of struggle?
- No.
- 그럼 누굴 죽였다는 거야?
- 모르겠어요
- And who did they kill?
- I don't know.
백인 남자였고, 180cm 정도에
90kg쯤 나가 보였어요
It was a guy.
Male, caucasian, 5'11", 200 pounds.
배리 본즈에 관해 싸우고 있었는데
보면 확실히 알아볼 수 있습니다
They were arguing about Barry Bonds.
And I'm pretty sure that I can ID him.
- 야구 선수 배리 본즈?
- 네
- The baseball player?
- Yeah.
그 남자는 블룸 박사가 배리 본즈를
납치했다고 생각하나 봐요
I think this guy thought
Dr. Bloom kidnapped Barry Bonds.
배리 본즈의 가치가 얼마나
나가는지에 대해 싸웠다니까요
I mean, they were arguing about
how much Barry Bonds was worth.
자네, 치과 의사가 야구를 하면
무슨 팀 소속인 줄 알아?
Hey, you know, if your dentist played baseball,
you know what team he'd play for?
양키즈 팀이야. 알겠어?
(Yank : 잡아당기다, (이를)뽑다의 뜻)
The Yanks. Get it?
재미없어
It's not funny.
조금은 재밌는데, 뭘
It's a little funny, Randy.
랜디, 자네 말이야...
Look, why don't you, um...
산책 좀 하고
머리 좀 비우게
take a walk.
Clear you head.
자, 몽크 사무실에 이거 갖다줘
기다리고 있을 거야
Here, drop this off at Monk's.
He's waiting for this.
그리고 오늘은 쉬어
영화도 보러 가고 해변에도 가 봐
Then take the rest of the day off, okay?
Go to the movies, go to the beach.
알겠지? 나가 봐
Okay? Get out of here.
나중에 전화하지
I'll call you later.
이게 다야? 전체 파일이 이거야?
Is this everything? The whole file?
네
Yeah.
질문 하나 해도 돼요?
Monk, can I ask you a question?
의뢰비를 보통 얼마나 받으세요?
What do you normally charge?
사건 하나 맡으실 때마다요
You know, for someone
who wants to hire you.
경찰서에서 받는 것 말고
개인적으로 고용할 때요
I mean, not the department.
A private party.
누가 고용할 때?
Like who?
제가요
Like me.
그 치과 의사 얘기인가 봐요?
Is this about the dentist?
경감님한테 전화 왔어. 자네가
마취 부작용을 겪었다고 하시던데
The captain called us. He said you
had a reaction to the anesthesia.
- 아마 환각을...
- 아뇨. 환각이 아닙니다
- You were probably hallucinating...
- No, I wasn't hallucinating.
정말 일어난 일이에요
It really happened.
제 앞에 몽크 씨가 서 계신 것처럼
진짜로 일어난 일이에요
It was as real as you are right now
standing in front of me.
랜디, 난 지금 안 서 있는데
Randy, I'm not standing.
만약에 내 도움이 필요하면
돈은 안 내도 돼
But if you need my help...
you don't have to pay me.
그냥 부탁만 하면 돼
All you have to do is ask.
내 오래된 친구 중 하나잖아
우리가 알고 지낸 게 얼만데
I mean, you're one of my oldest friends.
I've known you for years.
고마워요. 치과로 저랑 같이
다시 가 주셨으면 해요
Thank you. I want you to come back
to the dentist's office with me.
내 말 다 안 끝났어
Let me finish.
안타깝지만 내가 지금
진행하고 있는 일이 너무 많아
Unfortunately, at the moment,
I have a lot of things on my plate.
안 그러시잖아요
No, you don't.
이 현금 수송차 사건이 있잖아
Well, I have this armored car thing.
총 120쪽은 되는 파일을
읽어 봐야 해
I have to read this whole file
that's about 120 pages.
어쨌든 지금 오타도 하나 찾았어
And I just found a typo, by the way.
그리고 빨래 건조기의
보푸라기 방지 필터도 갈아줘야 해
And I have to replace
the lint filter on my dryer.
필터가 저절로 교체되지는 않잖아
Filters do not replace themselves.
- 몽크 씨, 잠깐 얘기 좀 할까요?
- 그리고 나탈리랑 잠깐 얘기도 해야 해
- Mr. Monk, can I talk to you for a minute?
- I have to talk to Natalie for a minute.
- 둘이서만요
- 네?
- Privately?
- What?
부엌에서요
In the kitchen?
- 지금요
- 알았어요 / 어서요
- Now.
- Okay. / Go.
몽크 씨, 랜디가 부탁하잖아요
몽크 씨를 위해 뭐든 할 사람이라고요
Mr. Monk, this is Randy we're talking about.
He would do anything for you.
나도 뭐든지 해 줄 거예요
이것만 빼고요, 나탈리. 이건 못 해요
And I would do anything for him
except this, Natalie. I can't do it.
치과 의사는 좀 불편해요
I have a thing about dentists.
- 몽크 씬 뭐든지 불편하잖아요
- 맞는 말이죠
- You have a thing about everything.
- That's true,
근데 치과 의사는 완전히
새로운 종류로 불편한 거예요
but dentists are in a separate
category altogether, okay?
입에 담기도 싫어요
입에 담는다는 생각조차 싫어요
I can't even discuss it.
I can't even think about discussing it.
입에 담는다는 생각을
입에 담는 것조차 싫다고요
I can't even talk about
thinking about discussing it.
몽크 씨, 누구나 치과는 싫어해요
Mr. Monk, everybody's afraid of dentists.
이것처럼은 아닐걸요
이것처럼은 아니에요
Not like this.
알았어요, 알았어
얼마나 무서우신데요?
Okay, okay, okay.
How afraid are you?
10점을 최고로 치고
점수를 매겨 보세요
On a scale of 1 to 10.
10점요. 10점 한참 위예요
나탈리의 10점은 우스울 정도로요
10. I am so far beyond 10,
I laugh at your 10s.
10점 생각으로
밤을 꼴딱 새울 정도로요
I lie awake at night dreaming about 10s.
그 의자며 기구며 드릴에
또 입 헹구는 건 정말...
The chair and the probing and
the drilling and the rinsing.
그럼, 몽크 씨, 만약에 충치 생기면
어떻게 하세요?
Okay, Mr. Monk, what do you do
when you get a cavity?
충치 없어요
난 충치 같은 거 안 키워요
I don't get a cavity.
I don't get cavities.
하루에 12번 이 닦고
90분마다 치실로 닦아 낸다고요
I brush my teeth 12 times a day
and I floss every 90 minutes.
- 그럼 치과에 가 본 적이 없으시겠군요
- 딱 한 번, 12살 때 가 봤어요
- So you've never been to a dentist.
- Once, when I was 12.
어땠는데요?
How'd that go?
별로 안 좋았죠
Not well.
이건 진짜 말도 안 돼요
가서 한번 둘러보기만 해요
You know, this is ridiculous.
We're just gonna go there and look around.
환자로 가는 것도 아니고
의자에 눕지도 않을 거예요
You're not a patient.
You're not sitting in the chair.
입 안을 검사하는 일도 없을 거고
드릴도 없을 거예요
There's no probing.
There's no drilling.
그리고 제가 계속 옆에 있을게요
I'll be with you the whole time.
- 그런데...
- 아뇨
But I... / No.
기꺼이 하시겠대요
He's happy to do it.
잘됐군요
Great.
수상한 건 없어 보이는데요
I don't see anything.
저쪽 방에서 일어났어요
B번 방요
It happened in the other room.
Room B.
어떤 것 같아요?
What do you think?
몽크 씨
Psst, Mr. Monk.
분명 나치도 이렇게 벙커를
꾸몄을 거라고 확신해요
I'm pretty sure this is how the Nazis
decorated their bunkers.
저거 보지 마세요
아래를 내려다보세요
Don't look at that.
Look, look, look, look down.
카펫을 보세요
카펫이 얼마나 예뻐요
Look at the carpet.
What a beautiful carpet.
- 정말 예쁜 카펫이네요
- 그렇죠? 좀 나아졌어요?
- It is a beautiful carpet.
- Right? Is that better?
이러니 좀 낫군요
That is better.
아이들을 위한 하이라이트래요
Oh, highlights for children.
숨은 그림 찾기라
이거 정말 좋아했는데
Oh, find the hidden picture.
I used to love these.
달걀 거품기가 어디 있을까?
Where is the egg beater?
썰매 밑에 있어요
It's under the sled.
맞아요
You're right.
그리고 우산은 눈사람 위의
구름 안에 있어요
And the umbrella is in the cloud
above the snowman.
그리고 물고기는 스케이트 옆에 있어요
And the fish is next to the ice skate.
도대체 어떻게 하시는 거예요?
Okay, how are you doing that?
똑같은 걸 35년 전에 읽었어요
I read that same issue 35 years ago.
그때 내가...
It was in the...
치과에 있었을 때에요
it was in...
the dentist's office.
나탈리, 이건 못하겠어요
Natalie, I can't do this.
아니, 아니, 아니에요
할 수 있어요
Yeah, no, no, no, no, no,
you can do this.
할 수 있으세요
지금도 잘하고 계세요
You can do this.
You're doing great.
자, 자, 여기 앉아서
다른 걸 생각해 보세요. 아셨죠?
Okay, here, here, here, sit down
and think about something else, okay?
여기 사건 파일 가져왔어요
Here, I brought the case file.
여기에 집중해 보세요
Concentrate on this.
경위님, 치료를 더 받으시려고 오셨어요?
Lieutenant. You back for more?
아뇨, 아뇨
No, no.
사실은 제가 제 휴대폰을...
Actually, I think
I just left my cell phone...
B번 방에 놓고 간 것 같아서요
in the chair in room B.
지금 비었으니까
한 번 둘러보세요
Oh, well, it's empty now
if you wanna take a look.
잘됐네요
Great.
전 나탈리인데, 경위님을 도와주러 왔어요
물건을 제대로 못 찾으시거든요
Oh, I'm Natalie, I'm just gonna help him.
He can't ever find anything.
금방 돌아올게요
바로 저기에 있을게요. 괜찮으시겠어요?
I'm gonna be right back.
I'm gonna be right here. Are you okay?
네, 네, 괜찮아요
Yeah. Yeah, I'm good.
제가 의자에 누워 있었는데
Okay, I was in the chair.
저쪽에서 싸웠어요
And they were fighting over there.
근데 아무것도 없는 것 같은데요
Okay, well, I don't see anything.
새 장비를 샀어요
He bought new equipment.
싸울 때 장비가 고장 나서
새 장비를 산 거라고요
He bought new equipment to replace
the stuff that got broken during the fight.
그럴지도요
Maybe.
- 뭐지?
- 드릴 소리예요
- What's that?
- It's a drill.
무서워하지 말아라
Don't be afraid.
안 무서운데요
I'm not afraid.
무서워하지 마
Don't be afraid.
무서워하면 안 돼
몽크 씨, 이제 괜찮아요
Mr. Monk, it's okay.
이제 집에 갈 거예요
놓으셔도 돼요
We're gonna go home now.
You can let go.
안 돼요. 아직 못 갑니다
몽크 씨가 아무것도 안 봤잖아요
No, no, we're not going anywhere.
He hasn't seen anything yet.
- 충분히 보신 것 같은데요
- 괜찮으십니까?
- I think he's seen enough.
- Is there a problem?
아닙니다. 제가 저쪽 방에
휴대폰을 놓고 가서요
Oh, no, no, I just left
my cell phone in the other room.
선생님, 이쪽은 에이드리안 몽크 씨입니다
제 친구세요
Dr. Bloom, this is Adrian Monk.
He's a friend of mine.
그 유명한 탐정 에이드리안 몽크 씨요?
만나서 정말 반갑군요
The Adrian Monk, the detective?
It's a pleasure to meet you.
저만 반가운가 보네요
Apparently, the pleasure's all mine.
치과 의사를 좀 불편해 하셔서요
No, he just has a little
thing about dentists.
사실은 자주 있는 일이죠
You know what?
It happens to me all the time.
저는 개의치 않습니다
I don't take it personally.
제가 주워 드리죠
Let me help you with that.
아, 현금 수송차 사건을 수사하고 계세요?
Oh, are you working
on the armored car case?
이 얘기 읽어 봤죠
전 실제 범죄 이야기를 좋아하거든요
I've been reading about it.
I'm a bit of a true crime aficionado.
죄송해요. 기밀 사항이라
I'm sorry, that's just classified.
그럼 취미가 두 개시겠군요?
실제 범죄하고 야구 말입니다
Well, you got a couple of hobbies then, huh?
True crime and baseball.
야구요?
Baseball?
네. 두 분이서 어제 배리 본즈에 관한
얘기를 하는 걸 분명히 들었습니다
Well, yeah, I'm sure I heard you guys
talking about Barry Bonds yesterday.
보통 사람들은 마취되면
이상한 게 들린답니다
Well, you know what?
People hear a lot of crazy things
when they're under sedation.
또 이상한 얘기도 많이 하시죠
책으로 내도 될 정도입니다
They say a lot of crazy things too.
I should write a book, really.
네, 알았어요
Yes, sir, I understand.
네, 곧 갈게요
가야겠어요. 경감님이세요
Okay, we're on our way.
We gotta go, that was the captain.
- 가야 하네요
- 그러세요
- Oh, we gotta go.
- Okay.
안녕히 가세요
Take care.
낚시꾼 두 명이 발견했어
A couple of fishermen just found him.
25cm 간격으로
두 군데 멍이 들었어요
These two bruises, ten inches apart.
그리고 정확히 25cm 간격으로
찍힌 멍이 또 한 쌍 있고요
There's another set of bruises
exactly ten inches apart.
그렇군. 무엇 때문일까?
Yeah, what caused that?
틀림없이 25cm 간격이 있는
물건일 겁니다 / 대단히 고맙군
Well, it must be something
ten inches apart. / Thanks a lot.
근데 뭘 발견하셨어요?
중요한 거라고 하셨잖아요
Well, what do you got?
You said it was important.
바지 속에서 찾았어
I found this in his trousers.
바짓단에 있더군
플렉시 유리야
It was in his pants cuff.
It's plexiglas.
- 납치범 중의 한 명이겠군요
- 이자가 구멍을 뚫은 거야
- It's gotta be one of the hijackers.
- He drilled the hole.
그럼 누구죠?
So who is he?
뒤집어 봐
Turn him over.
- 난 누군지 모르겠어. 자네는?
- 저도 모르겠어요
- I don't recognize him, do you?
- No.
말도 안 돼
Oh, my god.
이 사람이에요
치과에서 봤던 그 사람이에요
That's the guy.
That's the guy from the dentist's office.
- 랜디, 가서 쉬랬잖나
- 아뇨, 아뇨
Randy, I told you to
take some time off. / No, no.
경감님, 이 사람입니다
제가 알아볼 수 있다고 했잖아요
Captain, that's the guy.
I told you I could ID him.
분명히 이 사람입니다
And that is definitely the guy.
치과 의사와 치위생사가 죽인 게
이 사람이라고? / 맞습니다
What, this is the guy that your dentist killed
along with his hygienist? / That's right.
자네가 치료 받을 때 자네 코앞에서
죽인 사람이란 말이지? / 맞아요
This the guy that they killed in front of you
while you were in the chair. / That's right.
그렇군. 블룸 박사가
배리 본즈를 납치해서
All right, because Dr. Bloom
kidnapped Barry Bonds,
이 사람하고 몸값에 대해
싸우던 중에 말이지?
and they were arguing
about the ransom money, right?
네, 그렇게 미친 소리처럼 들립니까?
뭐가 그렇게 웃겨, 패터슨?
Yeah, what, is that so crazy?
What the hell are you laughing at, Peterson?
- 저 미친놈 아닙니다
- 아무도 그런 얘기는 안 했어요
I'm not crazy. / Okay, nobody said
you were crazy, Randy.
들리게 안 한 거죠 / 정신 좀
번쩍 들게 사랑니나 심어 달라지 그랬어
Out loud. / While you were there you
should've had them put some wisdom teeth in.
당신은 사랑니 철자도 모르잖아요
Hey, you can't even spell
wisdom teeth, Downey.
- 나탈리
- 네?
- All right, look, Natalie.
- What?
몽크랑 거기에 있었죠?
자네가 보기엔 어땠나?
You and Monk were there, right?
Did you notice anything?
제 상태가 말이 아니었어요
치과에 가면 굉장히 불편해서요
No, I wasn't really on my game.
I have this thing about dentists.
크로거 박사님은 그걸
슈퍼울트라 공포증이라고 부르시죠
Kroger calls it a supermegaphobia.
세균이 이쯤이고 뱀이 이쯤이면
치과 의사는...
If germs are here and snakes are here,
the dentists are...
저기 나뭇가지 보이세요?
위에서 두 번째 거요?
You see that branch up there?
The second one from the top?
그것보다 위에쯤이에요
The one above that one.
경감님, 수사하실 겁니까
안 하실 겁니까?
Captain, are you going to
investigate this or not?
랜디, 자넨 마취 중이었잖나
아무것도 못 봤을 거라고
Randy, you were sedated.
You couldn't have seen anything.
그럼 그만두죠
Fine, I quit.
- 뭘 어째?
- 그만둔다고요
- You what?
- No, I quit.
동네 바보처럼 취급 받는 것도
아주 신물이 납니다
I'm sick and tired of being treated
like the village idiot.
- 총이랑 배지 돌려 드리죠
- 랜디, 이러지 말게
- Here's my gun and my badge.
- Randy, come on.
농담하는 거 아니에요
I'm not a joke.
경감님 웃기려고 근무하는 게 아닙니다
I'm not here to entertain you.
저도 강력계 형사라고요
I'm a homicide detective.
랜디, 이러지 말게
Randy, don't be ridiculous.
받으세요
Take it.
랜디
Randy.
경감님, 사체 신원이 밝혀졌습니다
Captain, they just ID'ed the body.
들어 보시겠어요?
Are you ready for this?
데니 자딘입니다
It's Denny Jardeen.
- 그 이름 알지
- 네, 전직 경찰이에요
- Ooh, I know that name.
- Yeah, he's an ex-cop.
미션 지구에서 근무했는데
아주 골칫덩이였더군요
Worked the Mission District.
He was bad news.
다섯 번이나 고발당했어요
권력 남용에 행실도 나빴습니다
He was charged five times.
Excessive force, conduct unbecoming.
4년 전에 조기 퇴직으로 물러났어요
Took an early retirement four years ago.
고맙네
Thanks.
- 뭐 하는 겁니까?
- 치실로 닦아 내고 계세요
- What's he doing?
- Flossing.
치과에 다시는 안 가기로
결심하셨거든요
He's determined never to
go back to a dentist again.
- 저 없는 셈 치세요
- 몽크, 그만 하게. 정말이야
- Uh, just pretend I'm not here.
- Monk, cut it out, I mean it.
여긴 치실 금지 구역이야
This is a floss-free zone.
- 언제부터요?
- 지금부터
- Since when?
- Since right now.
그만 하게
Cut it out.
- 이게 뭐예요?
- 아무것도 아니에요
- What's this?
- That's nothing.
올리버 블룸에 대한 뒷조사잖아요
그 치과 의사에 대해 신원 조회하셨어요?
Background check Oliver Bloom.
You're checking out the dentist?
네. 한번 조사해 봐도
해될 것 없다 싶더군요
Yeah, I figured it couldn't hurt
to check him out.
랜디를 위해서 하셨던 거군요?
You're doing this for Randy, aren't you?
그냥 전화해 보지 그러세요?
Why don't you just call him?
제 발로 걸어 나갔잖아요
Because he quit.
랜디도 성인이고
Randy is an adult.
자기가 결정을 했으니
전 그걸 존중합니다
He made a decision and I respect it.
그리우시잖아요
딱 보여요
You miss him, I can tell.
나탈리, 랜디랑 내가 무슨
애인 사이도 아니었잖아요
Look, Natalie, it's not like
we were going steady, okay?
같이 근무했을 뿐입니다
다른 경찰과 다를 바 없었어요
We worked together.
He was just another cop.
그렇지 않잖아요
That is not true.
맞아요. 사실이 아니죠
다른 경찰과는 확실히 달랐죠
You're right, it's not true.
He's not just another cop,
경찰 배지 단 사람 중에
가장 짜증 나는 인간이었죠
he was the single most annoying
human being to ever wear a badge.
이 방에 있는 사람 제외하고
Present company excepted.
자, 얘들아
이 새 노래 불러 보자
Okay, you guys,
let's try this new one.
내가 가사 뽑아 왔어
I printed up some lyric sheets.
우리가 왜 가사가 필요해?
노래는 너만 부르잖아
Why do we need lyric sheets?
You're the only one singing.
그래야 너희도 따라오지
뭐에 관한 내용인지도 알고
Just so you can follow along.
So you know what it's about.
- 우린 메시지를 담는 거야
- 우리가?
- We're making a statement.
- We are?
해 보자. 처음부터 가자고
Okay, let's do it, from the top.
5, 6, 7, 8
A five, six, seven, eight.
잠깐, 잠깐!
그게 뭐야?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What was that?
- 박자 세잖아
- 5, 6, 7, 8?
- Counting off.
- Five, six, seven, eight?
- 5, 6, 7, 8?
- 그건 춤출 때나 하는 거라고
- 아냐
- That's for dancing.
- No, it's not.
1, 2, 3, 4라고 해야지
You're supposed to go,
"one, two, three, four."
그게 그거지!
Come on, what's the difference?
이건 로큰롤이야, 임마
It's rock 'n roll, man.
전에 하던 블루스곡이나 불러 보자
Let's do that blues song
we used to do.
얘들아
야, 야, 얘들아!
Guys.
Guys, guys, guys!
얘들아, 그냥 하던 거에 집중하자. 응?
Hey, guys, guys, why don't we just
stick to the original material, okay?
관중들은 록을 듣고 싶어한단 말이야
I mean, that's what the people wanna hear.
무슨 관중들?
여긴 우리 새 아빠 차고라고
What people? Randy,
we're in my stepfather's garage.
애론, 언젠가는 관중들이 생길 거야
Well, Aaron, there might
be people one day.
순회공연 다니고
음반도 계약하면 말이야
I mean, touring, record deal?
이런 게 우리들 꿈 아니었어?
Come on, guys, wasn't that the dream?
17년 전에 고3 때나 그랬나?
Maybe 17 years ago in 12th grade?
근데 난 말이야
Well, you know what?
난 아직도 그 꿈을 믿어
I still believe in the dream.
랜디 디셔 프로젝트를 믿는다고
I mean, I believe in
the Randy Disher project.
- 난 이거 때문에 일도 관뒀어
- 큰 실수 하셨군
- Come on, I quit my job for this.
- Big mistake.
그냥 해 보자고. 알았지?
All right, let's just do it, okay?
처음부터
From the top.
또 5, 6, 7, 8이라고 하면
나 그만둘 거야
If you say "five, six,
seven, eight" again, I quit.
정말이야
I'm just telling you.
그럼 네가 리드 싱어 하고 싶어?
That's good. You know what?
Do you wanna be the lead singer?
실례합니다
Excuse me.
여기 믹 재거하고
잠시 얘기 나눌 수 있을까요?
Can I talk to Mick Jagger for a second?
그럼요
Yeah, sure.
잠깐만 쉬자
All right, guys, take a break, huh?
아, 지금까진 아주 좋았어
정말 좋았어
Oh, it's a really good job
so far, though. Really good.
- 잘돼 가나?
- 그럼요
- How's it going?
- It's good.
아주 좋습니다
진작에 할 걸 그랬어요
It's great. I mean, I should
have done this years ago.
그래. 꽤 신나 보이는군
Yeah, it's pretty exciting.
나중에 티셔츠나 모자 같은 거
나오면 좀 보내 줘
Um, you gotta send me a T-shirt
or a hat or something.
다른 것도 좋고...
Or whatever.
이 얘기 듣고 싶어할 것 같아서
현금 수송차 사건에 실마리가 잡혔어
Um, listen, I thought you might be interested.
We caught a break on the armored car thing.
사체 신원 확인이 됐는데
데니 자딘이라는 친구야
We identified the body.
Guy's name is Denny Jardeen.
전직 경찰이고
He's an ex-cop.
그 친구 사촌이 전과자인데
지금 트럭 회사에서 일하고 있더군
He's got a cousin who's done some time
who works for a trucking company.
그래서 지금 붙잡으러 갈 건데
자네도 같이 가고 싶어할 것 같아서
So we're gonna go pick him up.
I thought you'd like to come along.
왜요?
Why?
전 이제 경찰이 아니에요, 리랜드
I mean, I'm not a cop anymore, Leland.
경감님
Captain.
제 수첩 보세요
Look at my notebook.
이제 목격자 진술은 없고
전부 가사하고 작곡 아이디어예요
No more witness statements.
Just lyrics and song ideas now.
- 노래도 쓰나?
- 네. 어젯밤에 17곡을 썼어요
- You're writing songs?
- Yeah, I wrote 17 last night.
완전히 불붙은 것 같아요
I'm on fire.
확실히 그런 것 같구먼
I'm sure you are.
그리고 그 치과 의사에 관해서
사과도 하고 싶었네
Uh, I also wanted to apologize
about the dentist.
자네가 지난 몇 년간 꽤...
It's just that over the years
you've had...
- 특이한 추리를 많이 했잖나
- 환각을 본 게 아니에요
- so many unique theories.
- I wasn't hallucinating.
랜디, 근무 시간 끝나고 내가 직접
블룸 박사의 뒷조사를 해 봤는데
Randy, I checked Dr. Bloom out
myself on my own time.
깨끗한 사람이야
The guy is clean.
전과도 없고
사고 친 적도 없어
He's got no priors.
He's never been in trouble.
내가 자네 말을 심각하게
받아들였다는 걸 알아줬으면 하네
I just wanted you to know
that I took you seriously.
사실은 말이지
The fact is...
자네가 그립고
자네가 필요하네
I miss you, I need you.
이젠 너무 늦었어요
Well, it's too late.
전 다 잊었어요
I've moved on.
이 밴드가 이제 제 전부예요
I mean, the band's my life now.
원하시면 한번 들어 보세요
대환영입니다
You're more than welcome to come
and have a listen if you want.
어서 들어오세요
Come on in, be my guest.
앉으세요
Have a seat.
그러지
안녕하세요?
Okay.
How you doing?
안녕하세요?
Hey.
미리 말씀드리는데, 아마
듣기 거북하실지도 모릅니다
I should warn you,
you might not like what you hear.
꽤 힘 있는 노래거든요
감당 못하실 수도 있어요
It's pretty powerful stuff.
You might not be able to handle it.
좋아. 멋지게 불러 보자고
All right, let's rock it out.
처음부터
From the top.
1, 2, 3, 4
One, two, three, four.
5, 6, 7, 8
Five, six, seven, eight.
♪ 아부하는 것도 이젠 질렸어 ♪
♪ I'm tired of sucking up ♪
♪ 아부하는 것도 질렸고
남 밑에서 일하는 것도 질렸어 ♪
♪ and I'm tired of sucking up
and working for the man ♪
♪ 나에게 법이 허락해 준 대로
사람들 억압하는 것도 질렸어 ♪
♪ keeping people down
'cause the law says I can ♪
♪ 형제들에게 수갑을 채우다니
그건 옳지 않아 ♪
♪ cuff my brothers and sisters
that's not the way to be ♪
♪ 하지만 그런 날들은 지났어 ♪
♪ but honey those days are gone ♪
♪ 왜냐하면 난 자유롭기 때문이지 ♪
♪ 'cause baby I am free ♪
♪ 옳고 그름을 구별하는 데
배지 따윈 필요하지 않아 ♪
♪ I don't need a badge
to tell me wrong from right ♪
♪ 낮과 밤을 구별하는 데
경찰 배지는 필요 없어 ♪
♪ I don't need a badge
to tell me day from night ♪
♪ 배지 따윈 필요 없어
이제 난 눈을 떴으니까 ♪
♪ I don't need a badge
because my eyes can see ♪
♪ 배지 따윈 필요 없어
왜냐하면 난 자유로우니까 ♪
♪ I don't need a badge
'cause baby I am free ♪
좋았어
나쁘지 않았는데
All right, that was good.
That wasn't too bad.
아주 훌륭했네
That was great.
자, 문을 두드리기 전에
Okay, now, before you even
knock on the door,
이 손수건을 클로로포름으로
적시는 거야
I want you to douse this handkerchief
with the chloroform.
이렇게 말이야. 알겠지?
Just like this, okay?
20cc만큼 적셔
확실히 들이마시게 하고
20 ccs, and make sure
he really inhales it.
이래도 되는지 모르겠어요
I don't know about this.
꼭 해야 해
선택의 여지가 없어
Well, we have to do it,
there's no choice.
아뇨. 제 말은 20cc가 충분하냐고요
No, no, I know.
I mean, I don't know if 20 ccs is enough.
그 사람이 얘기할지
어떻게 아세요?
How do you know he's gonna talk?
그 사람 봤지?
Did you see him?
나랑 악수도 못했어
완전히 얼어 있었잖아 / 맞아요
He couldn't even shake my hand.
He was a mess. / Yeah.
에이드리안 몽크를 여기로 데려오면
You get Adrian Monk in here,
내가 불게 만들 거야
and I'll make him talk.
닐, 네 지문이 창고와
수송차에 온통 찍혀 있었어
Neal, your fingerprints were all over
the warehouse and on the armored car.
여기서 제일 잘나가는 변호사를 써도
그 지문들이 없어지진 않지
You could hire the best lawyer in the city.
It's not gonna make those
fingerprints disappear.
다 끝났어. 자네도 알잖나
It is all over and you know it.
거기 있긴 했지만
경비원을 어쩌진 않았어요
Okay, I was there.
But I didn't do the two guards, man.
- 오히려 말리려고 했다고요
- 누굴 말려?
- I tried to stop him.
- Stop who?
데니요
Denny.
데니 자딘요
Denny Jardeen.
경비원 한 명이 반항하자
데니가 열 받아서 총을 쏘기 시작했죠
One of the guards fought back and he
went postal, man. And started shooting.
돈은 어디 있나, 닐?
Where's the money, Neal?
데니가 갖고 있어요
Denny's got it.
돈을 나눌 때까지 자기 집 뒤쪽
창고에 보관하기로 했어요
He's keeping it in a shed back behind
his place until we all split it up.
안 좋은 소식이 있네, 닐
데니는 죽었어
I got some bad news for you, Neal.
Denny is dead.
- 데니가요?
- 그리고 그 창고엔 돈도 없었어
Denny? / And there's no money
in that little tool shed.
우리가 벌써 구석구석 뒤져 봤어
We've already ripped it apart.
말도 안 돼요
Now that's impossible.
자네 패거리 중에
누가 욕심이 생겼나 보군
Looks like somebody in your
little sewing circle got greedy.
요샌 정말 믿을 놈이 없다니까
안 그렇나?
You can't trust anybody
these days, can you?
몽크 씨
Oh, Mr. Monk.
늦은 줄 알지만
들어가도 돼요?
I know it's late.
Can I come in?
그럼요, 그럼요
Of course, of course.
고마워요
Thank you.
왜 그러세요?
What, what is it?
디셔 경위님 말이 맞아요
Lieutenant Disher was right.
이틀 전에 블룸 박사님이 사람을 죽였어요
Dr. Bloom killed a man two days ago.
근데 전 그게 누군지도 모르겠어요
And I don't even know who it was.
생전 처음 보는 사람이었거든요
I mean, I'd never seen him
before or anything.
- 다른 데 갈 데가 없었어요
- 괜찮아요
- I just don't know where else to go.
- Yeah.
근데 계속 많이 울 생각인가요?
Yeah, are you gonna be crying a lot?
그럼 싱크대에 숙이고 있는 게
나으실 거예요
Maybe you wanna lean over the sink.
아니에요, 괜찮아요
죄송해요
No, no, I'm fine.
I'm sorry.
그냥 너무 무서워서 그래요
I'm just scared to death.
- 그럼 제가 경감님께 전화할게요
- 안 돼요!
- Yeah, I'll call the captain, right?
- No!
블룸 박사님이 절 죽일 거예요
전화하시면 안 돼요
No, Dr. Bloom would kill me.
You can't.
괜찮아요
Oh, it's okay.
경찰이 보호해 줄 거예요
The police will protect you.
어머, 그거 뭐예요?
Oh, what is that?
- 뭐, 뭐요?
- 잘 모르겠어요
- What, what?
- I don't know.
- 뭔데요?
- 잘 모르겠어요
- What is it?
- I don't, it's right...
얼굴 위에 뭐가 묻었어요
얼룩처럼요
it's a something on your face.
Like a smudge.
얼룩이요 / 네
Smudge. / Yeah.
아직 못 지우셨어요
바로 거기 있잖아요
No. No, you're not getting it.
It's right there.
- 지워졌어요?
- 아뇨
- Did I get it?
- No.
제가 해 드릴게요
가만히 계세요
Here, I'll do it.
Hold on. Okay.
지워졌어요?
Did you get it?
- 안 지워졌어요?
- 아뇨, 바로 여기에요
- No?
- No, it's right there.
클로로포름이군요
Chloroform.
날 마취시키잖아요
You're drugging me.
긴장 푸세요
Just relax.
지웠어요?
Did you get it?
지워졌어요?
Did I get it?
Did I get it.
- 나탈리!
- 경감님, 몽크 씨 여기 계세요?
- Natalie!
- Captain, is Mr. Monk here?
몽크가 여기 왜 있겠어요?
나도 여기 왜 있는지 모르겠는데
What would Monk be doing here?
I don't even know what I'm doing here.
평소처럼 내일 날씨를 읽어 드리려고
전화했는데 받질 않으시더라고요
I called his house to read him
tomorrow's weather report like I always do,
but he didn't answer.
그래서 가 봤더니 문은 열려 있고
불도 켜져 있는데 댁에 안 계시지 뭐예요
So I go over there, the door's open.
The light's on, but he's not home.
문이 열려 있었다고요?
The door was open?
기다려 주셔서 감사합니다
선생님이 곧 오실 거예요
Thank you for waiting.
The doctor will be right with you.
서두를 것 없어요
There's no rush.
왜 이러는 거예요?
Why are you doing this?
왜 이러는 거냐고요?
이러지 말아요
Please.
제발요
이제 어쩌실 거예요?
What are you gonna do?
얼룩 같은 거 없었죠?
I didn't really have a smudge, did I?
영광인 줄 아세요
You should be flattered.
선생님이 보통 이렇게 늦게는
안 봐주시거든요
The doctor doesn't usually
come in this late.
더군다나 새 환자일 경우에는
Especially for new patients.
저 이빨 모형
That tooth.
뿌리가 25cm 간격이죠?
The roots are about
ten inches apart, aren't they?
맘대로 생각하세요
If you say so.
이제 이해가 가네요
어떻게 된 건지 알겠어요
I get it now.
I know what happened.
트럭을 납치하는 동안
운전사가 반항했고
The drivers fought back
during the hijacking.
데니 자딘이 얼굴을 맞았어요
Denny Jardeen got hit in the face.
그래서 이가 흔들거린 거죠
He must have knocked a tooth loose.
자딘도 이를 치료하러 여기에
왔던 겁니다. 말이 되네요
So Jardeen came here to get
his tooth fixed. Makes sense.
그 사람도 전직 경찰이었고
여기가 의료 보험 지정 병원이니까요
He's an ex-cop,
and you're on the medical plan.
자딘은 마취 중에 말했던 거예요
He must have talked in his sleep.
많은 환자가 그런다고 블룸 박사도
그랬어요. 자딘이 전부 얘기한 겁니다
Dr. Bloom said a lot of patients do.
He told you everything.
강도에 관해서나
어디에 돈을 숨겼는지도
About the robbery,
where they hid the money,
복권 당첨된 기분이었을 거예요
it must have been like
winning the lottery.
맘대로 생각하세요
If you say so.
그날 밤 자딘의 집에 가서 돈을 찾았고
무사히 끝났다고 생각했겠죠
That night, you went to Jardeen's house,
found the money, figured it was safe.
당신들한테 말했다는 걸
기억하지 못할 테니까
That he'd never remember
telling you anything.
근데 당신들이 틀렸어요
But you were wrong.
자딘이 기억해 낸 거예요
He did remember.
아니면 돈이 없어진 걸 보고
Or maybe, when the money
went missing,
그냥 알았는지도요
he just figured it out.
랜디를 치료하던 화요일 밤에
자딘은 여기로 돌아왔던 겁니다
He came back here Tuesday night
while you were working on Randy.
랜디가 전부 다 봤던 거예요
대충은요
Randy witnessed the whole thing,
sort of.
랜디 말이 전부 맞았던 거예요. 맞죠?
He was right about everything,
wasn't he?
맘대로 생각하세요
If you say so.
다시 오셨군요, 몽크 씨
Hello, again, Mr. Monk.
치과에 딱 한 번 와 봤다는 말이
사실이세요? / 네
Is it true that you've only
been to the dentist once before? / Yeah.
별로 좋은 기억은 아니었나 보군요
I gather it wasn't a good experience.
그럼 이번은 더 안 좋은
추억이 될 겁니다
Well, this'll be much worse.
전...
I'm...
전 경찰관이에요
I'm a police officer.
압니다
Oh, I know that.
그게 바로 몽크 씨가 여기 계신 이유죠
That's precisely why you're here.
테리하고 제가...
좀 팔고 싶은 물건이 있습니다
You see, Terri and I, we have...
some merchandise we'd like to sell.
입 벌리세요
Open, open, open.
예금 증서가 좀 있거든요
Some bank certificates.
마침 시카고의 크로닌 씨라는 사람이
저희 물건을 사고 싶어해요
Now, there's a man in Chicago named
Mr. Cronin who would like to buy them.
근데 접근하기가 좀 그래요
But we're afraid of approaching him.
경찰이 감시하고 있는지 어떤지
잘 모르겠거든요
Because we don't know
if he's being watched by the police.
그러니까 대답해 보세요
So my question is...
경찰이 크로닌 씨를 감시하고 있어요?
is Mr. Cronin under surveillance?
전 몰라요
I don't know.
몽크 씨, 혹시 '마라톤 맨'이란
영화를 본 적 있으세요?
Have you ever seen
the movie 'Marathon man', Mr. Monk?
아뇨. 재밌나요?
No, is it good?
같이 봐요
Let's watch it.
우리 지금 같이 봐요
Let's, let's watch it now.
전 영화를 별로 좋아하진 않지만
I'm not much of a movie guy,
제가 지금 시간은 좀 있거든요
but I have some time now.
누가 나오는데요?
Who's in it?
누가 나오는 영화죠?
Who's in that?
그 영화를 볼 게 아니라
그 영화처럼 되실 거예요
You're not gonna watch it,
you're gonna live it.
(영화 '마라톤 맨'에 치과 기구로
사람을 고문하는 장면이 나옴)
크로닌 씨를 감시하고 있나요?
네, 아니요로 대답하세요
Is Mr. Cronin under surveillance?
Yes or no.
정말 몰라요
I don't know.
정말 나도 알았으면 좋겠어요
I wish I did. I really do.
근데 정말로 몰라요
But I don't know.
- 크로닌 씨를 감시하고 있어요?
- 아니요!
- Is Mr. Cronin under surveillance?
- No!
- 그 사람을 감시하고 있습니까?
- 네, 그래요
- Is he under surveillance?
- Yes. Okay, yes.
감시하고 있어요
Yes. We know...
경찰이 전부 다 알고 있어요
we know all about it.
그러니까 조심해야 할 거예요
You have to be careful.
조심해야 한다고요
You should be careful.
저도 정말 몽크 씨 말을
믿고 싶습니다
Now, I really wish
I could believe you, Mr. Monk.
치아 상태가 완벽해요
Your teeth are perfect.
충치가 하나도 없어요
I don't see a single cavity.
크로닌 씨를 감시하고 있어요?
Is Mr. Cronin under surveillance?
아무 말도 안 할 거예요
He's not saying anything.
이뽑이 겸자 좀 건네줘
Pass me the extractor please.
'랜디 디셔 프로젝트'가 뭐가 문젠지
아직도 모르겠어
I still don't see what's wrong
with the Randy Disher project.
그 이름이 맘에 안 들었어
I never liked that name.
고등학교 다닐 때도
Even in high school.
그랬군
Okay.
그럼 '랜디 디셔 체험단'은 어때?
Okay, what about
the Randy Disher experience?
'심각한 타이어 손상'은 어떠셔?
How about severe tire damage?
그럼 '부드러운 기사단'은 어때?
Okay, how about mellow knights with a K?
난 '랜디 디셔 체험단' 쪽으로
맘이 끌리는데
I gotta say I'm leaning towards
the Randy Disher experience.
그럼 이렇게 하자
How about this?
신문을 펼쳐서
제일 처음 눈에 띄는 단어가
I'm gonna open up a newspaper
and the first word I see...
우리 밴드 이름이 되는 거야
that's our name.
바그다드
Baghdad.
괜찮은데
맘에 들어
That's good actually.
I kind of like that.
- 바그다드라
- 잠깐 줘 봐
- Baghdad.
- Let me see that.
천3백만 달러의
무기명 채권이 도난당하다
$13 million in bearer bonds stolen.
무기명 채권(Bearer bonds)
배리 본즈(Barry Bonds)
Bearer bonds. Barry Bonds.
배리 본즈가 아니었어
Not Barry bonds.
그 사람들은 무기명 채권을
얘기하고 있었던 거야!
They were saying bearer bonds!
알았어요! 알았다고요!
잠깐, 잠깐만요
All right!
All right, okay! Wait, wait.
지금 그 손은 너무 더러워요
Your hands are so dirty.
- 뭐라고요?
- 제발...
- Excuse me?
- Could you...
제발 먼저 손 씻고 와 주세요
you gotta wash your hands first.
Please.
- 나보고 손 씻으라고요
- 제발요
- You want me to wash my hands.
- Please.
- 전 손 안 씻을 겁니다. 알았어요?
- 부탁드릴게요
- I'm not gonna wash my hands, okay?
- Please.
손 안 씻을 거라고요
가만히 계세요
I'm not washing my hands.
Okay, now, just hold still.
우린 동물이 아니잖아요
제발, 이렇게 부탁드립니다
We're not animals, here, right?
Please, I'm asking you.
부탁드릴게요
I'm asking you.
- 영화에선 손을 씻긴 했어요
- 영화 얘긴 꺼내지 마
- He did wash his hands in Marathon man.
- Don't give me "In Marathon Man."
- 고문하면서 무슨 손을 씻어
- 5초밖에 안 걸릴 거예요, 제발
I'm not gonna wash my hand when
I'm torturing him. / It'll take,
it'll take five seconds, please.
이렇게 사정할게요!
I'm asking you!
자비를 베푸세요. 제발요
제발 부탁입니다
Look into your heart. For god.
For the love of god.
부탁입니다
자비를 베푸세요
For all that's holy.
Look into your heart.
- 제발 봐주세요
- 그놈의 손 씻으면 되잖아요
- Look into your heart.
- I'll wash my damn hands, okay?
봐요, 불이 켜져 있어요
Look, the lights are on.
아뇨, 그게 아니에요!
그 비누로 씻으면 안 돼요
No! No, not the wrong soap.
- 항박테리아 비누로 씻어야죠
- 드릴 줘 봐 / 그 비누는 안 돼요!
- You gotta use the anti-bacterial soap!
- Give me the drill. / Not the wrong soap!
이 정도면 봐준 거예요
드릴 이리 줘
All right, this is enough, already.
Just give me the drill.
그 비누가 아니란 말이에요
Not that soap.
드릴 내려놔!
의자에서 떨어져!
Drop the drill!
Step away from the chair!
- 들어오지 말아요, 나탈리. 밖에 있어요
- 순순히 지시에 따라요
- Don't move, Natalie. Stay there.
- Easy, you too.
저쪽으로 가요
Get over here.
무릎을 꿇어요
둘 다요
Down. Down on your knees now.
Both of you.
괜찮나?
You okay?
- 저 수갑 없는데요
- 여기 있네
- I don't have my cuffs.
- Here.
- 손 내미세요
- 몽크 씨, 이젠 괜찮아요
- Give me your hands.
- Mr. Monk, it's okay, it's okay.
다 지나갔어요
It's all over.
다 끝났어요
♪ 강하다고 느끼기 위해
총을 가질 필요는 없지 ♪
♪ I don't need a gun
to make me feel strong ♪
♪ 하루 종일 날 못살게 구는
상사도 필요 없지 ♪
♪ I don't need a captain
shoot me down all day long ♪
♪ 당신의 콧수염도 필요 없어
나에게 몸을 낮추지 마 ♪
♪ I don't need your moustache
don't you condescend to me ♪
♪ 난 아무도 필요 없어
난 자유로우니까 ♪
♪ I don't need nobody
'cause baby I am free ♪
♪ 난 아무도 필요 없어
난 자유로우니까 ♪
♪ no I don't need nobody
baby I am free ♪
에너지가 넘치는데요
Wow, that had some good energy.
그러게, 에너지가 철철 넘치는군
Yeah, a lot of energy.
나중에 같이 다시 보세
Let's watch it again sometime.
이젠 상관없어요
어차피 밴드가 깨졌거든요
It doesn't matter.
I mean, the band broke up anyway.
뭐 하나 의견 일치를 본 게 없었어요
We couldn't agree on anything.
밴드 이름도 그랬고
무슨 음악을 할지도 못 결정했어요
Name, what kind of music to play.
제가 입을 다물어야 할지 말지도요
Or whether or not I should shut up.
이리 오게
Come here.
이거 자네 물건인 것 같은데
I believe this is yours.
돌아와서 반갑네, 랜디
Welcome back, Randy.
잘 돌아왔어
Welcome back.
괜찮으세요?
Are you okay?
- 이가 흔들려요
- 네?
- Loose tooth.
- Huh?
몽크 씨를 쓰러뜨릴 때
그랬나 봐요
I betcha that happened
when they knocked him out.
세상에, 치과에 가 보셔야겠어요
Oh, gosh, you gotta see a dentist.
아니에요
Nah.
몽크 씨, 무서워하실 것 없어요
Mr. Monk, there's nothing to be afraid of.
그리고 제가 계속 옆에 있을게요
What, I'll be with you the whole time.
또 다른 치과 의사가 몽크 씨를
고문할 확률이 얼마나 되겠어요?
What are the odds of
another dentist torturing you?
그 얘긴 이제 하지 말자고요
Let's not talk about it anymore.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)